Subject Files
Marist Archives and Special Collections
Subject Files
2.1.3.6
Marist College
  Box 1537 - Box 1540
- Subject Files, 2.1.3.6
  Box 1541 - Box 1544
- Subject Files, 2.1.3.6
  Box 1545
- Subject Files, 2.1.3.6
  - Subject files: First World Flight, 1924; 1 (Box 1545)
    - [A huge crowd gathers to greet the First World Fliers], 1
    - [A man presenting (something?) to the memebers of the First World Flight], 2
    - [An aviator from the First World Flight walking across a stage], 3
    - [A plane from the First World Flight], 4
    - [Two men involved in the First World Flight], 5
    - [Aviator involved in the First World Flight getting ready to take off], 6
    - [Man on the shore waving to two planes from the First World Flight], 7
    - [An aviator from the First World Flight shaking hands with a woman], 8
    - [Aviators in the First World Flight surrounded by people], 9
    - [An aviator from the First World Flight standing with a woman], 10
    - [Members of the First World Flight being greeted by a woman], 11
    - [A man involved in the First World Flight (?)], 12
    - [A crowd of people greeting the First World Fliers], 13
    - [A group of people cleaning (?) a plane from the First World Flight], 14
    - [A member of the First World Flight], 15
    - [A member of the First World Flight], 16
    - [A member of the First World Flight], 17
    - [A member of the First World Flight], 18
    - [A member of the First World Flight], 19
    - [A member of the First World Flight], 20
    - [A member of the First World Flight], 21
    - [A member of the First World Flight], 22
    - [First World Flight planes going through a straight], 23
    - [A woman pinning a flower into the jacket of a First World Flier], 24
    - [First World Flier shaking hands with an officer], 25
    - [A woman hitting (?) a First World Flight plane], 26
    - [Man in the water-from the First World Flight], 27
    - [First World Flight plane landing in a field], 28
    - [First World Flight planes coming in for a landing in Alaska. Caption: The 4 World Cruisers entering above Reserrection Bay, Seward, Alaska. ], 29
    - [First World Flight aviators talking in front of their "Chicago"plane], 30
    - [Aviators in the First World Flight surrounded by a group of people], 31
    - [First World Flight planes over a city], 32
  - Subject files: First World Flight, 1924; 2 (Box 1545)
    - [Lowell Thomas holding a racoon], 1
    - [Lowell Thomas (on left) with aviators of the First World Flight], 2
    - [Man in the cockpit of a First World Flight plane], 3
    - [First World Flight planes parked by camels], 4
    - [Woman standing in front of the "New Orleans"plane from the First World Flight], 5
    - [Three planes flown in the First World Flight], 6
    - [An aviator from the First World Flight holding his pet racoon], 7
    - [Members of the First Worlf Flight], 8
    - [Shot of one of the planes flown in the First World Flight], 9
    - [First World Flight plane getting ready for take off], 10
    - [Aviators of the First World Flight boarding their plane], 11
    - [Aviators in the first world flight had to take a boat from their plane to the shore.], 12
    - [First World Fliers landed in a grassy field being greeted by children], 13
    - [Two First World Fliers], 14
    - [Two First World Flight planes in front of a snowy mountain], 15
    - [Three First World Flight aircrafts flying in front of the sun], 16
    - [Member of the First World Flight], 17
    - [First World Flight plane landing in water as men in a rowboat watch], 18
    - [Men working on the First World Flight "New Orleans" plane], 19
    - [First World Flight planes parked by some camels], 20
    - [First World Flight planed moored off a coast], 21
    - [A woman holding two stuffed monkeys with First World Flight members], 22
    - [First World Flight plane in flight], 23
    - [First World Flight plane in water], 24
    - [First World Flight plane in front of mountains], 25
    - [Two First World Flight planes in front of a snowy mountain], 26
    - [First World Flight plane flying over a bay], 27
    - [First World Flight plane flying over a forest], 28
    - [View of snow-capped mountains from a First World Flight plane], 29
    - [View of a small town from a First World Flight plane], 30
    - [First World Flight plane flying over a city], 31
    - [First World Flight plane in front of a seaside cliff], 32
    - [A member of the First World Flight], 33
    - [The First World Flight planes flying around snow-covered mountains], 34
    - [Two First World Fliers holding stuffed monkeys], 35
    - [Member of the First World Flight leaning on a plane], 36
    - [First World Flight plane landing in icy water], 37
    - [First World Flight plane moored in icy water], 38
    - [October 25: Aviator standing on a First World Flight plane], 39
    - [Man standing with a large pole; taken during the First World Flight], 40
    - [First World Flight plane in the water in front of snowy mountains], 41
    - [First World Flier sitting with cans of gas (?)], 42
    - [Boat sailing through icy water; taken during the First World Flight], 43
  - Subject files: First World Flight, 1924; 3 (Box 1545)
    - [First World Flight planes moored to shore], 1
    - [First World Flight aviators standing in front of their plane], 2
    - [First World Flight members shaking hands], 3
    - [First World Flight plane coming in for a landing over a city], 4
    - [First World Flight plane in air], 5
    - [People waiting for the arrival of the First World Fliers], 6
    - [View of a steep cliff from a First World Flier plane], 7
    - [Young girl; taken from the First World Flight], 8
    - [Man pinning badges onto a First World Flier], 9
    - [First World Flight plane in an exhibit], 10
    - [First World Flight plane in an exhibit], 11
    - [First World Flight team (?) holding a portrait of a woman], 12
    - [First World Flight planes over a city], 13
    - [A crowd of people waiting to greet the First World Fliers (?)], 14
    - [First World Flight plane landing in a field], 15
    - [First World Flight plane landing in a field], 16
    - [Aviators of the First World Flight working on their plane], 17
    - [First World Flight planes moored to shore], 18
    - [Members of the First World Flight], 19
    - [First World Fliers gathered around a document on a table], 20
    - [Aviators of the First World Flight standing in front of a plane labled, "Air Service U.S.A. World Flight"], 21
    - [Two First World Flight planes flying by snow-capped mountains], 22
    - [First World Fliers standing in front of one of their planes], 23
    - [Caption: Commissioned officers to World Flight. Left to right: Lt. John Harding, ORO. Lt. Erik H. Nelson, Lt. Leigh Wade, Major Frederick L. Martin, Lt. Leslie P. Arnold, Lt. Lowell H. Smith, Lt. LaClair D. Schulze], 24
    - [First World Flight aviator waving from his plane], 25
    - [First World Flight plane on a crane], 26
    - [A large crowd gathered around a First World Flight plane], 27
    - [The wreck of a (?); taken during the First World Flight], 28
    - [Two First World Flight planes flying by snowy mountains], 29
    - [Citizens of Japan welcoming the First World Fliers by waving American flags], 30
    - [First World Fliers working on their plane], 31
    - [A crowd welcoming the First World Fliers], 32
    - [A crowd gathered to watch the First World Flight plane take off (?)], 33
    - [Man standing on the wreck of a plane (?); taken during the First World Flight], 34
  - Subject files: First World Flight, 1924; 4 (Box 1545)
    - [Comissioned officers to the First World Flight], 1
    - [Lowell Thomas (? Middle) standing with officers of the First World Flight], 2
    - [Lowell Thomas (on right ?) and another aviator of the First World Flight sitting in their plane], 3
    - [Statue of a man on a horse in a city; taken during the First World Flight], 4
    - [Boats rowing out to meet the First World Flight planes], 5
    - [First World Flight plane sitting in the water, snowy mountain in the background], 6
    - [Man wearing a pointy hat; taken during the First World Flight], 7
    - [Men rowing in a canoe by the shore], 8
    - [Two First World Flight planes above the clouds], 9
    - [Two children standing in front of a mound of dirt; taken during the First World Flight], 10
    - [First World Fliers], 11
    - [Men of the First World Flight looking at a woman walking down the street], 12
    - [First World Flight plane moored in the water in front of a snowy mountain], 13
    - [A First World Flier taking a picture with a group of children in Alaska (?], 14
    - [Members of the First World Flight riding on camels], 15
    - [First World Flier with a cigarette holding two stuffed monkeys], 16
    - [Three First World Flier planes above a rainforest], 17
    - [Man standing in icy water; taken during the First World Flight], 18
    - [Three First World Flight planes passing a boat], 19
    - [A ship covered in ice; taken during the First World Flight], 20
    - [First World Flier holding a flag from inside his plane], 21
    - [Officers of the First World Flight standing on "The Olympian"], 22
    - [Men pushing a First World Flier plane (for take-off?), 23
    - [Two First World Flier planes above fields], 24
    - [A ship sailing through the ice], 25
    - [Three First World Flight planes going over a city], 26
    - [First World Flier signing his autograph for a woman], 27
    - [Members of the First World Flight sitting in the snow], 28
    - [A manin a white hat; taken during the First World Flight], 29
    - [The United States Capitol taken from a First World Flight plane], 30
    - [A crowd gathered around the First World Fliers], 31
    - [A man in a white hat; taken during the First World Flight], 32
    - [First World Flight planes in flight], 33
    - [Two aviators of the First World Flight], 34
    - [A crowd gathered to welcome the First World Fliers], 35
  - Subject files: First World Flight (reunions), circa 1959 - 1970s; 5 (Box 1545)
    - [Lowell Thomas (on right) and other members of the First World Flight at a reunion], 1
    - [Lowell Thomas (on right) and other members of the First World Flight at a reunion], 2
    - [Lowell Thomas standing with other members of the First World Flight some years later], 3
    - [Lowell Thomas standing with other members of the First World Flight some years later], 4
    - [Lowell Thomas and other past aviators of the First World Flight standing in front of one of their planes], 5
    - [Lowell Thomas and other past aviators of the First World Flight standing in front of one of their planes labled "Air Service U.S.A. World Flight"], 6
    - [Lowell Thomas (on left) with other members of the First World Flight at a reunion], 7
    - [Lowell Thomas standing with two previous First World Fliers], 8
    - [Lowell Thomas being presented with a commemorative plaque of the First World Flight], 9
  - Subject files: First World Flight (airplane crash), undated; 6 (Box 1545)
    - [Airplane crash; taken during the First World Flight], 1
    - [Aviator of the First World Flight standing by the remains of an airplane], 2
    - [Aviator of the First World Flight looking at the pieces of an aiplane crash], 3
    - [Aviator of the First World Flight examining the engine of a plane wreck], 4
    - [The engine (?) of a wrecked plane], 5
    - [Aviator of the First World Flight looking at the remains of a plane], 6
    - [The remains of a plane crash; taken during the First World Flight], 7
    - [Aviator of the First World Flight standing by the remains of an aiplane], 8
    - [The remains of a plane crash; taken during the First World Flight], 9
    - [Aviator of the First World Flight standing by the remains of an aiplane], 10
    - [Aviator of the First World Flight holding an anchor and leaning on the remains of a plane from the First World Flight], 11
    - [Lowell Thomas Jr. (?) examining the engine of a crashed plane], 12
    - [Aviator from the First World Flight looking at the engine of a crashed plane], 13
  - Subject files: Harrison Forman and Chairman Mao Tse-Tung [Zedong], 1944; 7 (Box 1545)
    - Harrison Forman with Chairman Mao Tse-Tung; Yenan, North China - 1944; Photo made during World War II when Harrison Forman was a War Correspondent based in Chungking, the wartime capital. Mr. Forman was the first American newsman invited to visit the regions controlled by the Chinese Communists in North China. His book, REPORT FROM RED CHINA, recounting his talks with the Red leaders, and travels with their troops in military actions against the Japanese, created a sensation when published in America. It was translated into fifteen foreign languages including Chinese, 1
    - Verso: Harrison Forman with Chairman Mao Tse-Tung; Yenan, North China - 1944; Photo made during World War II when Harrison Forman was a War Correspondent based in Chungking, the wartime capital. Mr. Forman was the first American newsman invited to visit the regions controlled by the Chinese Communists in North China. His book, REPORT FROM RED CHINA, recounting his talks with the Red leaders, and travels with their troops in military actions against the Japanese, created a sensation when published in America. It was translated into fifteen foreign languages including Chinese, 1-verso
  - Subject files: Fox MovieTone, circa 1930s; 8 (Box 1545)
    - In MovieTone studio, 10th avenue and 54th street [2 copies], 1
    - Note: In MovieTone studio, 10th avenue and 54th street, 2
    - Movietone Teams: Ed Thorgerson - sports; Lew Lehr - comic; Louise Vance - fashion; Lowell Thomas - news; recording for MovieTone News, 3
    - Note: Movietone Teams: Ed Thorgerson - sports; Lew Lehr - comic; Louise Vance - fashion; Lowell Thomas - news; recording for MovieTone News, 4
    - The Movietone Team:-LT, Louise Vance, fashions; Lew Lehr, humor; Ed Thorgerson, sports, 5
    - Verso: The Movietone Team: -LT, Louise Vance, fashions; Lew Lehr, humor; Ed Thorgerson, sports, 5-verso
    - [Left to right Laurence Stallings, Editor, Truman Talley, Producer, and Lowell Thomas, voice & editor of 20th cent-Fox Movietone-for 20 years.], 6
    - Verso: [Left to right Laurence Stallings, Editor, Truman Talley, Producer and Lowell Thomas, voice & editor of 20th century-Fox Movietone- for 20 years.], 6-verso
    - [Detective with a magnifying glass leaning on a CBS microphone], 7
    - Verso: Lew Lehr, 7-verso
    - [Man in checkered suit holding a cigar], 8
    - Verso: Lew Lehr, 8-verso
    - [Man in suit blowing a pipe], 9
    - Verso: Lew Lehr, 9-verso
    - Set - Fox MovieTone "short", 10
    - Verso: Set - Fox MovieTone "short", 10-verso
    - MovieTone set below ballfield at Clover Brook, 1930s [4 copies], 11
    - Verso: MovieTone set below ballfield at Clover Brook, 1930s, 11-verso
    - [Lowell Thomas and the cast of a Fox MovieTone short], 12
    - [On the set of a Fox Movietone short], 13
    - [Dancing scene from a Fox Movietone short], [2 copies], 14
    - [Scene from a Fox Movietone short], 15
  - Subject files: French Legion of Honor, 1938; 9 (Box 1545)
    - Note: Pictures made on May 5, 1938 when L. T. was made a Knight of the Legion of Honor by the French Government. Presentation made by French Ambassador, Count Rene Doynel de Saint-Quentin. The French Consul General, Chas de Fontnouvelle, was also present, and he is pictured here with L. T. and Saint-Quentin., 1
    - Mr. Lowell Thomas in May was decorated a Knight of the Legion of Honor by the French Ambassador, 2
    - Verso: Mr. Lowell Thomas in May was decorated a Knight of the Legion of Honor by the French Ambassador, 2-verso
    - Lowell Thomas decorated a Knight of the Legion of Honor by the French Ambassador, 3
    - Lowell Thomas decorated a Knight of the Legion of Honor by the French Ambassador [6 copies], 4
    - Verso: French Consul General Chas de Fontnouelle May 5 - 1938; Knight of Legion of Honor, 4-verso
  - Subject files: Friends [includes color photographs], undated; 10 (Box 1545)
    - [Friend of Lowell Thomas], 1
    - Caption: For Christl Thalhammer with very best wishes, Conrad N. Hilton, Los [Angeles?] Sept. 6th 1968, 2
    - Stone from La Popa, famed convent in Cartagena, Colombia. Convent built following early discovery and was destroyed during pirate hold on the city in 16th century and earlier. Shot here is Marcia and Perry Weimer where the stone was selected atop the convent; Sent 1940 to Lowell, 3
    - Note: Stone from La Popa, famed convent in Cartagena, Colombia. Convent built following early discovery and was destroyed during pirate hold on the city in 16th century and earlier. Shot here is Marcia and Perry Weimer where the stone was selected atop the convent; Sent 1940 to Lowell, 4
    - Stone (square) from the ruins atop the famed Sachuaman Fortress in Cuzco, Peru. Effort to get this out was tremendous and only thru our mutal [sic] associations did the government allow this. I placed the stone in this position only for the photo. It had a rounded or semi square smaller rear side that indicated it may have been a $$$$$$ hinge or an anchor for whatever purpose. Shot here was made in November 1940 in Peru at the fortress. Marcia carried it in her coat until we returned to safety? it is one of a kind, 5
    - Note: Stone (square) from the ruins atop the famed Sachuaman Fortress in Cuzco, Peru. Effort to get this out was tremendous and only thru our mutal [sic] associations did the government allow this. I placed the stone in this position only for the photo. It had a rounded or semi square smaller rear side that indicated it may have been a $$$$$$ hinge or an anchor for whatever purpose. Shot here was made in November 1940 in Peru at the fortress. Marcia carried it in her coat until we returned to safety? it is one of a kind, 6
    - Doolittles, 7
    - Note: Doolittles, 8
    - Dr. Vilhjalmur Stefansson and some of the Camp Hale boys, in snow house - being built for instruction; Winston Pote, Photographer, Lancaster, N.H., 9
    - Verso: Dr. Vilhjalmur Stefansson and some of the Camp Hale boys, in snow house - being built for instruction; Winston Pote, Photographer, Lancaster, N.H., 9-verso
    - Mr. R.J. Finnegan; Moffett Studio, 30 S. Michigan Ave., Chicago 3, Ill., 10
    - Verso: Mr. R.J. Finnegan; Moffett Studio, 30 S. Michigan Ave., Chicago 3, Ill., 10-verso
    - Mr. Charles G. Ross taken at The White House about 1948; From Mrs. Roy A. Roberts, 814 Rockwell Lane, Kansas City, Mo. 64112; Please credit U.S. Army Photograph, 11
    - Verso: Mr. Charles G. Ross taken at The White House about 1948; From Mrs. Roy A. Roberts, 814 Rockwell Lane, Kansas City, Mo. 64112; Please credit U.S. Army Photograph, 11-verso
    - Hans Faulkner - [?], 12
    - Verso: Hans Faulkner - [?], 12-verso
    - Norman Dyhrenfurth; Photograph by Richard C. Powers, 13
    - Verso: Norman Dyhrenfurth; Photograph by Richard C. Powers, 13-verso
    - "Newsreel" Wong - August, 1974 - R. N. [?], 14
    - Verso: "Newsreel" Wong - August, 1974 - R. N. [?], 14-verso
    - Chas. Ross, 15
    - Verso: Chas. Ross, 15-verso
    - Richard St. Barbe Baker;The Man of the Trees, 16
    - Verso: Richard St. Barbe Baker;The Man of the Trees, 16-verso
    - Elliott V. Bell, 17
    - Verso: Elliott V. Bell, 17-verso
    - Tunney and creator of Maggie and Jiggs [Gene Tunney, left, George McManus, right], 18
    - Verso: Tunney and creator of Maggie and Jiggs [Gene Tunney, left, George McManus, right], 18-verso
    - Sir Hubert Wilkins; Photographed at the Waldorf Astoria by Leo Borr, 19
    - Verso: Sir Hubert Wilkins; Photographed at the Waldorf Astoria by Leo Borr, 19-verso
    - Harry G. Thomas [center], Herbert Hoover [right], 20
    - Verso: Harry G. Thomas [center], Herbert Hoover [right], 20-verso
    - [President Franklin Delano Roosevelt] Roosevelt makes his tenth "Fireside" chat. Pictured in the oval room of the White House, President Roosevelt is shown as he gave to the nation his tenth "Fireside" chat to the nation. Earlier President Roosevelt announced a special session of Congress, Oct. 12th; Oct 1937, 21
    - Note: [President Franklin Delano Roosevelt] Roosevelt makes his tenth "Fireside" chat. Pictured in the oval room of the White House, President Roosevelt is shown as he gave to the nation his tenth "Fireside" chat to the nation. Earlier President Roosevelt announced a special session of Congress, Oct. 12th; Oct 1937, 22
    - Irene Curie-Joliot, Prof. Joliot, 23
    - Verso: Irene Curie-Joliot, Prof. Joliot, 23-verso
    - Arthur Godfrey, 24
    - Verso: Arthur Godfrey, 24-verso
    - Dr. [Alton] Ochsner, 25
    - Verso: Dr. [Alton] Ochsner, 25-verso
    - Dr. [Alton] Ochsner, 26
    - Dr. Alton Ochsner, Mrs. Robert C. Hills, first trip, 27
    - Verso: Dr. Alton Ochsner, Mrs. Robert C. Hills, first trip, 27-verso
    - Mr. Robert C. Hills former President of Free Port Minerals Company (silver necktie) now living in New Orleans; Alston, LT, Dr. Alton Ochsner; first trip, 28
    - Verso: Mr. Robert C. Hills former President of Free Port Minerals Company (silver necktie) now living in New Orleans; Alston, LT, Dr. Alton Ochsner; first trip, 28-verso
    - Erling Strom, riding among the golden larches of September at Assiniboine in the Canadian Rockies; Photo by Ethel Van Degrift, 29
    - Note: Erling Strom, riding among the golden larches of September at Assiniboine in the Canadian Rockies; Photo by Ethel Van Degrift, 30
    - [Painting of a man in a cowboy hat holding skiis], 31
    - [Man with glasses], 32
    - [Friend of Lowell Thomas], 33
    - [An announcer for NBC radio], 34
    - [Earl Strom standing with a horse], 35
    - Dr. Cortez Enloe at South Pole, 36
    - Verso: Dr. Cortez Enloe at South Pole, 36-verso
  Box 1546
- Subject Files, 2.1.3.6
  - Subject files: Friends, undated; 1 (Box 1546)
    - [A man and a woman kissing], 1
    - [A man standing with his wife (?)], 2
    - [A sailor], 3
    - [A man sitting at a banquet table], 4
    - [A young girl], 5
    - [A businessman standing in front of the Empire State Building (?)], 6
    - [A businessman waving his hat], 7
    - [A man in a cowboy hat], 8
    - [A man giving a speech], 9
  - Subject files: King George of Greece, circa 1940s; 2 (Box 1546)
    - Note: King of Greece, 1
    - King George of Greece. [2 copies], 2
    - Verso: King George of Greece., 2-verso
    - King George of Greece and L.T. at a Waldorf banquet [3 copies], 3
    - Verso: King George of Greece and L.T. at a Waldorf banquet, 3-verso
    - [Lowell Thomas with King George of Greece], 4
    - [Lowell Thomas with King George of Greece], [2 copies], 5
    - Elsa Maxwell, King of Greece and L.T., 6
    - Verso: Elsa Maxwell, King of Greece and L.T., 6-verso
  - Subject files: Floyd Gibbons, circa 1930s - 1940; 3 (Box 1546)
    - L.T., left; H.B. ("Buzz") Le Quatte, Floyd Gibbons, right, 1
    - Verso: L.T., left; H.B. ("Buzz") Le Quatte, Floyd Gibbons, right, 1-verso
    - Lowell Thomas inducting the Floyd Gibbons Post #500 into the national organization of the Veterans of Foreign Wars, at the Hotel Astor, September 1940. Its organizer and first Commander was Mike Finklestein, a newspaper man for sixty years, 2
    - Verso: Lowell Thomas inducting the Floyd Gibbons Post #500 into the national organization of the Veterans of Foreign Wars, at the Hotel Astor, September 1940. Its organizer and first Commander was Mike Finklestein, a newspaper man for sixty years, 2-verso
  - Subject files: Jack Girsham, tiger hunter [color photographs], 1958 - 1960s; 4 (Box 1546)
    - [Lowell Thomas standing with Jack Girsham, tiger hunter, [1.1, 4.2, 4.3, 4.4 on same sheet], 1
    - [Lowell Thomas speaking with Jack Girsham, tiger hunter], [1.1, 4.2, 4.3, 4.4 on same sheet], 2